Brennam Bond

Software Developer

Houston, TX | 832-465-7192 | brennambond@gmail.com | linkedin.com/in/brennambond/ | github.com/brennambond

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Software Developer with 2+ years of experience working with web-based technologies and frameworks to build full-stack apps that are designed well, developed fast, and that provide value. Strong technical knowledge and skills in areas including object-oriented design, flexible and service-based architecture, along with a keen interest in DevOps and agile software development methodologies and practices. An excellent communicator and problem-solver who loves working in dynamic, agile development environments. My portfolio: https://brennambondportfolio.vercel.app/.

SKILLS

<u>Front End:</u> JavaScript (w/ ES6+), TypeScript, HTML5, CSS3 (w/ SCSS), React (w/ Redux, Next.js) | <u>Back End:</u> Node.js (w/ Express), Python (w/ Django), PHP, Go, WordPress, PostgreSQL, MongoDB | <u>Infrastructure & Cloud:</u> Docker (w/ Kubernetes), AWS (w/ EC2, S3, Cognito, Lambdas, etc.) | <u>Version Control:</u> Git (w/ GitHub, GitLab) | <u>Testing:</u> Jest, Storybook

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Developer | Dec 2022 - Present Self-Employed | Houston, TX

Overview: Build, test, ship, and iterate full-stack applications using JavaScript along with TypeScript and React for frontend development workflow, Python, Node.js, or PHP to design and implement RESTful APIs, use PostgreSQL or MongoDB databases to write complex and optimized queries, and use Docker with AWS for infrastructure engineering and migration to cloud hosting.

- Created an events organization web application that allowed users to sign-up, create, and manage events. Users can add events to
 their cart and purchase event tickets with Stripe. Technologies used: Next.js, React, TypeScript, MongoDB, Node.js, Express, and
 Tailwind CSS.
- Designed a hotel-booking website where users can book stays from a selection of dozens of rooms. Technologies used: Next.js, React, TypeScript, Python, Django, PostgreSQL, Docker, and AWS. AI used to generate images via Midjourney.
- Built a performant e-commerce website where users can purchase from a selection of dozens of products, with authentication, cart, and checkout with Stripe features. Technologies used: Next.js, React, TypeScript, Python, Django, PostgreSQL, Docker, and AWS. AI used to generate images via Midjourney.

Production Assistant | Aug 2021 – Nov 2022 Penguin Random House | New York, NY

- Managed dozens of Young Adult novels for Random House Children's Books throughout their lifecycle, multi-tasking without
 loss of efficiency or composure, and executing on the agreed-upon timetables in conjunction with internal PRH teams and
 external vendors.
- Managed data via Excel and PRH's database to analyze data and improve cost-estimation accuracy, then managed that data via our enterprise software SAP to pull and create financial reports, manipulate key metadata, and issue purchase orders.
- Ran QA checks on final print files using InDesign, Photoshop, and Acrobat, archiving them within our archiving system once
 complete, using strong problem solving and decision making skills to ensure problems were solved while also using good
 judgement should any issues arise to quickly manage them.

Digital Publishing Assistant | Oct 2020 – Aug 2021 Self-Employed | Houston, TX

- Create author websites for independent and unpublished authors using programming languages like WordPress, HTML, CSS, and PHP, ensuring web standards were always met and using collaboration and creativity skills to better highlight the author's talents.
- Converted print files into digital content like eBooks using InDesign, optimizing text, incorporating and adjusting images, and creating essential landmarks such as table of contents and index pages for easy navigation both on desktop and mobile devices.
- Converted ePub files into MOBI, AZW3, and/or PDF files, uploading them to the Kindle, iBooks, or other e-reader websites, ensuring they aligned with the company's eBook-publishing specifications.

EDUCATION

Associate of Arts (AA) | Lone Star College | Cypress, TX | 2011-2013